yes today we're going to make craft
cheese
gelato I'm not sure about this one let's
just get on and do
[Music]
it so yeah craft cheese it's not really
a thing back in the UK it seems to be a
big thing in North America let's have a
look at the ingredients before we start
which is is dried whey from milk cheddar
cheese made from milk salt bacterial
culture modified Milk ingredients
microbial enzymes cream calcium chloride
lipase and anato salt U butter natural
flavorings paprika turmeric and anato
extracts citric acid and sodium
phosphate oh sounds
delicious nutritional information per
one
tablespoon so 6 G there
is5 G of fat 4 g of sugar 1 g of protein
and then various tiny little numbers so
quite high in sugar that will be the
Whey whey is 66% lactose so that's what
that is um going back to the ingredients
there's no added sugar to this so it's
literally all coming from the
lactose which is not a problem by the
way lactose is just not a sweet sugar
it's a natural sugar in Dairy so nothing
wrong with that unless you're lactose
intolerant then you know there is an
issue
let's open
this
thing smells like
feet
right what are we going to need we're
going to
need 436 G of milk 110 G of whipping
cream 75 G of our craft cheese powder
100 g of sugar 30 G of Dex rays and
we're going to use guar gum for this to
stabilize it as well so let's get on get
it on a hob and get this gelato going
so we've got our milk and cream in here
gently warming up we don't need to bring
this up to any specific temperature cuz
going to use guar gum which is a cold
mix stabilizer in here I've taken 10 G
of the recipe sugar combine that with
The Gua gum and we're going to leave
that aside here in here we have our
sugar our craft cheese powder and our
dextrose we're going to put all of that
into there and just whisk it up whilst
bringing it up to a warm temperature
make sure it's all completely dissolved
and
combined okay we're up to 52
CRA which is this in Fahrenheit for all
those people they don't like Cent grade
everything's dissolved nicely what we're
going to do is turn off the heat and
we're going to take our little mix of gu
gum and sugar pop that in there Stir It
Well just for about 30
seconds and there we're going to take it
off the heat put it in a container pop
it in the fridge for about 3 or 4 hours
until it's really chilled
[Music]
down so with your ice cream make it's
completely chilled down I've taken it
out lid off and it's got a really thick
kind of foamy stuff on the top of it
let's just mix it all back in and once
it's completely combined nice and smooth
texture we're going to pop it in our
machine and churn it it churned
surprisingly well as you can see really
creamy kind of texture to it color
lightened as you would expect anyway
let's get this in a container in the
freezer so we can dish them up and try
this craft cheese
gelato that is
yellow weirdly enough I can't smell
anything nope let's get some dished
up so there we go scooped up just as a
reminder I use this craft
powdered
cheese
okay what does this taste
like
it does Taste of craft
cheese I don't like the taste of craft
cheese but this wasn't about making an
ice cream that I personally
liked oh tastes
horrible this was about making an ice
cream out of a popular
ingredient call it what you like you can
make ice cream out of anything cheese
ice cream is quite popular in certain
parts of Asia
um I haven't had it there
either I want I would be interested in
making other cheese ice creams just not
this not all cheese in North America is
bad there are some really really good
cheeses over here in Canada anyway I
can't speak for America cuz I've not had
any over there but I am going to take a
punt and say that it's pretty similar
but there are some good cheeses over
here there absolutely are this is not
one of
them but but there you go texture-wise
it's really good gelato so you know low
fat if you love craft cheese and I know
there's an awful lot of you out there
that do like craft cheese then this is
an excellent ice cream to make
texture-wise it's really good super
smooth no ice crystals it's very craft
cheesy or as the Posh people say it's
very cheese forward tastes like feet
anyway thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe last
video of 2023 is going to be a Ben and&
Jerry's remake cuz I haven't done that
for a while and I actually quite enjoy
doing that so we're going to make what
is it we are going to make Ben and
Jerry's dirt cake top so if you're
interested in that with all its vanilla
pudding e ice cream then hit the
Subscribe button like comment do all
that kind of stuff and I will see you
next
[Music]
time